Guide to the Martin Harwit papers, 1957-1987
Harwit, Martin papers, 1957-1987
- VI. Research Projects
  - "Cryogenic Infrared Astronomy Environmental Research Satellite Study," Volume I, 1966 (Box 18, Folder 17)
  - "Cryogenic Infrared Astronomy Environmental Research Satellite Study," Volume II, 1966 (Box 18, Folder 18)
  - Mm-wave Infra-Red Astronomy Explorer (MIRAE) 3 (Box 18, Folder 19)
  - Mission Definition for Stanford Relativity Satellite, Final Report F71-07, Volume I (Box 18, Folder 20)
  - Dewar Test Flight for Stanford Relativity Mission, Volume I (technical) (Box 18, Folder 21)
  - Proceedings of Cryogenic Workshop, 1972 (Box 18, Folder 22)
  - Mission Definition for Stanford Relativity Satellite, Final Report, F-71-07, Volume III, Appendices (Box 18, Folder 23)
  - Infrared Rocket Astronomy notebook, 1965-67 (Box 18, Folder 24)
  - First Data Report: contract No. F19628-C-0128 (Box 18, Folder 25)
  - Kitt Peak National Observatory (KPNO), 1970-71 (Box 18, Folder 26)
  - KPNO, 1972-73 (Box 18, Folder 27)
  - KPNO Users Committee, 1971-72 (Box 18, Folder 28)
  - U.S. Naval Research Laboratory travel, 1963-65 (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - U.S. Naval Research Laboratory, Experiment No. NF 3.162RR (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - Program for an Orbiting Infrared Astronomical Observatory, 1964 (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - Rocket Launching Experiments, 1964-65 (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - Flight tests, No. 3.162RR (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - Field Operations, Experiment NF 3.162R, 1964-65 (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - Study, "The Interstellar Abundance of the Hydrogen Molecule: II. Galactic Abundance and Distribution", 1963 (Box 19, Folder 7)
  - Molecular Hydrogen and Nitrogen Research, 1962-65 (Box 19, Folder 8)
  - Naval Research Laboratory Registered Notebook, No. 9807 (Box 19, Folder 9)
  - Supplementary Specifications for the Mt. Pleasant Astronomical Observatory (Box 19, Folder 10)
  - Proposal to the NSF for Spectrometry of Far Infrared Interstellar Emission, 1970-72 (Box 19, Folder 11)
  - NSF Grant GP13543, "Detection of Infrared Interstellar Spectral Lines", 1968-71 (Box 19, Folder 12)
  - Block Associates Log Book, 1957-59 (Box 19, Folder 13)
  - Manuscript record book, 1958 (Box 19, Folder 14)
  - Manuscript notebook re. Spectrometry, 1972-73 (Box 19, Folder 15)
  - Committee on Rocket Research, 1969, 1972 (Box 19, Folder 16)
  - "Alignment of Interstellar Grains by Starlight." Paper published in Prague, Czechoslovakia, 1970 (Box 19, Folder 17)
  - Notebook with drawings on Echelle Development, 1979-81 (Box 19, Folder 18)
  - Dennis Ward's thesis notes, 1975-76 (Box 19, Folder 19)
  - Dennis Ward's lab book, 1975-76 (Box 19, Folder 20)
  - "Error Analysis for a Chopper-Modulated Infra-Red Detection System," by Tom Manwell. Cornell-Sydney University Astronomy Center (CSUAC) 116, 1967 (Box 19, Folder 21)
  - "The Influence of Planetary Perturbations upon the Spatial Orientations of the Orbits of Long-Period comets with Small Perihelion Distances," CSUAC 136 (Box 19, Folder 22)
  - Spectrometer notebook, 1976-77 (Box 19, Folder 23)
  - Application of a Random Event Quasar Model to the Optical Variability of 3C 273 by Tom Manwell and Michal Simon, CSUAC 112 (Box 19, Folder 24)
  - "Dissociation of Molecules by the Absorption of Line Radiation" by Michael W. Werner, CSUAC 314 (Box 19, Folder 25)
  - "Rocket Infrared Observations of the Galactic Center" by Baruch T. Soifer and J.R. Houck, Center for Radiophysics and Space Research (CRSR) 519, 1972 (Box 19, Folder 26)
  - "Jupiter: Its Infrared Spectrum from 16 to 40 microns" by James R. Houck, David Schaack and Robert A. Reed, CRSR 594, 1975 (Box 19, Folder 27)
  - "Paschen Line Observations of the Orion Nebula," by Michael W. Werner, Judith L. Pipher, Yervant Terzian and J.R. Houck, CRSR 308, 1968 (Box 19, Folder 28)
  - "Reddening Curves for Planetary Nebulae," by Judith L. Pipher and Yervant Terzian, CRSR 311, 1968 (Box 19, Folder 29)
  - "Black Paints for Far Infrared Cryogenic Use," by Judith L. Pipher and J.R. Houck, CRSR 389, 1970 (Box 19, Folder 30)
  - "A Lamellar Grating For Use with Infrared Spectrophotometers," by B.W. Jones and J.R. Houck, CRSR 399, 1970 (Box 19, Folder 31)
  - "Gravitational Deflection of Polarized Radiation," by John Broderick, Brian K. Dennison, Martin Harwit, David L. Jauncey, and R.V.E. Lovelace, CRSR 571, 1974 (Box 19, Folder 32)
  - Rocket Astronomy Studies sponsored by Advanced Research Projects Agency, 1970-71 (Box 19, Folder 33)
  - "Rocket Infrared Multicolor Observations of the Interplanetary Medium, H II Regions, and the Galactic Center Region," by Baruch Thomas Soifer, CRSER 503 (Box 19, Folder 34)
  - A Proposal to NASA for "A Multi-Bend Far-Infrared Survey with a Balloon-Borne Telescope", 1972 (Box 19, Folder 35)
  - "Observations of Interstellar Molecular Hydrogen," by Michael W. Werner, 1968 (Box 19, Folder 36)
  - "Spectrometer for Far Infrared Astronomy" and "Infrared Rocket Astronomy", 1970-71 (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - Proposal to NASA for "Research in Sequential Decoding", 1969-70 (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - Proposal to the Research Corporation for "Alignment of Interstellar Grains by Starlight", 1970-71 (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - A Proposal to NASA for "Spectrometry of Far Infrared Interstellar Emission", 1973 (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - Report to Air Force Cambridge Research Laboratories for "Spectrometer for Far Infrared Astronomy", 1971 (Box 20, Folder 5)
  - "Observations of Jupiter with a Hadamard Transform Spectrometer," report for Air Force Geophysics Laboratory, 1974-76 (Box 20, Folder 6)
  - "Infrared Observations of Diffuse Backgrounds," by Martin Harwit, James R. Houck, Barrie W. Jones, Judith L. Pipher and Baruch T. Soifer, 1971 (Box 20, Folder 7)
  - Goddard Detector Tests, 1981 (Box 20, Folder 8)
  - "The Far Infrared and Submillimeter Background," by J.R. Houck, Baruch T. Soifer, Martin Harwit and Judith L. Pipher, 1972 (Box 20, Folder 9)
  - "Error Analysis for a Chopper-Modulated Infrared Detection System" by Tom Manwell, 1969 (Box 20, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence and various projects, 1960-61 (Box 20, Folder 11)
  - Speaking engagements, 1962-63 (Box 20, Folder 12)
  - Naval Research Laboratory: "The Vertical Distribution of Water Vapor over Hyderabad, India, and Comparison with Mid-Latitude Distribution" - report no. 5817, 1962 (Box 20, Folder 13)
  - Travel notes and schedules, 1972-75 (Box 20, Folder 14)
  - Report to the NSF: "Infrared Night Sky Scanning Experiment," grant no. GP-1998, 1963-64 (Box 20, Folder 15)
  - Lectures on Far Infrared Rocket Astronomy, 1966 (Box 20, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence on "Far Infrared Rocket Astronomy", 1965-67 (Box 20, Folder 17)
  - North American Aviation, 1966 (Box 20, Folder 18)
  - One Year Research Work at the E.O. Hurlburt Center for Space Research at the U. S. Naval Research Laboratory, 1963 (Box 20, Folder 19)
  - Launching of an Infrared Sensing Telescope by Cornell University's Infrared Astronomy Group, 1967 (Box 20, Folder 20)
  - Air Force Cambridge Research Laboratory - Far Infrared Astronomy (Box 20, Folder 21-23)
  - Air Force Cambridge Research Laboratory - Aerobee Rocket Launch, 1970 (Box 20, Folder 24)
  - Pan Monitor correspondence - "Astronomical Observations in Far Infrared Astronomy" NASA contract no. 33-010-026, 1967-69 (Box 20, Folder 25)
  - Correspondence re. NASA contract no. NSR 33-010-026 (Far Infrared Rocket Astronomy), 1969-73 (Box 20, Folder 26)
  - Correspondence with NASA re. Infrared Rocket Astronomy, contract NSR 33-010-026, 1966-67 (Box 20, Folder 27)
  - Miscellaneous reports, notes and charts, contract NSR 33-010-026 (Infrared Rocket Astronomy), 1967 (Box 20, Folder 28)
  - Williams Laboratories, Inc. correspondence, NASA contract NSR 33-010-026, 1965-69 (Box 20, Folder 29)
  - Calendars (8) with ms. notes, 1972-79 (Box 20, Folder 30)
  - Travel notes and schedules (Box 20, Folder 31)
  - Personal diaries, 1981-86 (Box 20, Folder 32)
  - Correspondence with NASA on contract no. NSR 33-010-026 for Far Infrared Rocket Astronomy, 1965 (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence with NASA on contract no. NSR 33-010-026 for Far Infrared Rocket Astronomy, 1967-68 (Box 21, Folder 2-3)
  - Correspondence with NASA on contract no. NSR 33-010-026 for Far Infrared Rocket Astronomy, 1965-67 (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence with NASA on contract no. NSR 33-010-026 for Far Infrared Rocket Astronomy, 1968 (Box 21, Folder 5-6)
  - Electronics Tests and Launch report for Aerobee 150 Rocket, no. NF 3.162 sponsored by the Naval Research Laboratory, 1965 (Box 21, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence re. drawings for a liquid cooled rocket borne telescope, 1965 (Box 21, Folder 8)
  - NASA's Phase 2 Proposal for Cornell's Far Infrared Rocket Experiment Infrared Stellar Photometer Experiment NF 20.152 N.R.L. 402 blueprints, 1965 (Box 21, Folder 9)
  - Forman, Paul Legal Work, 2000 (Box 22, Folder 39)
  - SPECS Contract, 2004 (Box 22, Folder 40)
  - SWAS Report, 2005 (Box 22, Folder 41)
  - SWAS, 2004 (Box 22, Folder 42)
  - AAS Madison, 1995 (Box 22, Folder 43)
  - Harvard Trip, 1996 (Box 22, Folder 44)
  - China Trip, 1996 (Box 22, Folder 45)
  - Chicago Museum of Science and Industry, 1997 (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - Goddard, October 3 1997 (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - Cargese, May 4-15 1998 (Box 23, Folder 3)
  - Effore Majorana, 1998 (Box 23, Folder 4)
  - Glast, 1998 (Box 23, Folder 5)
  - Caltech, 1999 (Box 23, Folder 6)
  - Astronomische Gesellschaft, 1999 (Box 23, Folder 7)
  - Bonn, 1999 (Box 23, Folder 8)
  - Ames, 2000 (Box 23, Folder 9)
  - Alpbach, 2000 (Box 23, Folder 10)
  - Cornell, October 7 2000 (Box 23, Folder 11)
  - CalTech, October 22-26 2000 (Box 23, Folder 12)
  - Colgate, April 25, 2001 (Box 23, Folder 13)
  - Amer Phys. Soc., May 1 2001 (Box 23, Folder 14)
  - BF Goodrich, August 30 2001 (Box 23, Folder 15)
  - EPSI/ESP, 2001 (Box 23, Folder 16)
  - IPAC, 1999 (Box 23, Folder 17)
  - IPAC, No Date (Box 23, Folder 18)
  - ISO Correspondence, 1998 (Box 23, Folder 19)
  - Cargese Talk, 1996 (Box 23, Folder 20)
  - Leiden, October 22-24 2001 (Box 23, Folder 21)
  - Les Houches, August 3-28 1998 (Box 23, Folder 22)
  - Bronx Science Reunion, 1997 (Box 23, Folder 23)
  - Nantucket, July 1997 (Box 23, Folder 24)
  - NICMOS review, 1997-99 (Box 23, Folder 25)
  - Orion Nebula Clipping, 1998 (Box 23, Folder 26)
  - Paris, 1997 (Box 23, Folder 27)
  - Paris ISO Conference, 1998 (Box 23, Folder 28)
  - Santa Fe, 1998 (Box 23, Folder 29)
  - SVU August, 2000 (Box 23, Folder 30)
  - Sweden, 2000 (Box 23, Folder 31)
  - Tenerife, 1996 (Box 23, Folder 32)
  - Thessaloniki, July 1997 (Box 23, Folder 33)
  - Turkey Travel, 1992 (Box 23, Folder 34)
  - Williamsburg, April 1997 (Box 23, Folder 35)
  - Hayden Planetarium, 2002 (Box 23, Folder 36)
  - IIASA, 2001 (Box 23, Folder 37)
  - International Space University, 1995 (Box 23, Folder 38)
  - IPAC, March 1997 (Box 23, Folder 39)
  - ISSI, 2000 (Box 23, Folder 40)
  - Alpher- Miscellaneous, 1950 (Box 23, Folder 41)
  - Dispute with Peebles (Alpher Herunan/correspondence), 1965 (Box 23, Folder 42)
  - Miscellaneous, 1988 (Box 23, Folder 43)
  - Penzias, No Date (Box 23, Folder 44)
  - Dicke Interview, 1985 (Box 23, Folder 45)
  - Dave Wilkinson, 1985 (Box 23, Folder 46)
  - Peebles Wilkinson, 1985 (Box 23, Folder 47)
  - Peebles, 1985 (Box 23, Folder 48)
  - Herman and Alpher, 1985 (Box 23, Folder 49)
  - George Field on Background, 1985 (Box 23, Folder 50)
  - Alpher/Gruber Prize attempt, 2006 (Box 23, Folder 51)
  - Bethe: Woff Prize nomination, 1987 (Box 23, Folder 52)
  - APS Symposium, 1987 (Box 23, Folder 53)
  - Oral History Interviews by Martin Harwit, 1983 (Box 23, Folder 54)
  - Interviews by Martin Harwit, 1985 (Box 23, Folder 55)
  - Talks, 1978 (Box 23, Folder 56)
  - Jim Houck Birthday Ithaca, NY, 2000 (Box 23, Folder 57)
  - Rocket Flights, No Date (Box 23, Folder 58)
  - Airplane Observations, No Date (Box 23, Folder 59)
  - Hadanard Transform from Optics, No Date (Box 23, Folder 60)
  - Ames Talk 1994, 1994 (Box 23, Folder 61)
  - Paris, 1998 (Box 23, Folder 62)
  - Fourth Tetons Conference, 2000 (Box 23, Folder 63)
  - Japan, 1996 (Box 23, Folder 64)
  - Hayden Planetarium, 1999 (Box 23, Folder 65)
  - Box of Slides: Discovery, No Date (Box 24)
  - Box of Slides: Discovery and Understanding, No Date (Box 24)
  - Box of Slides: Understanding, No Date (Box 24)
  - Talks for Post-docs and students working on ISO, No Date (Box 24, Folder 1)
  - SIRTF Conference, 1998 (Box 24, Folder 2)
  - Laboratory Astrophysics, 2002 (Box 24, Folder 3)
  - Hadamard Transform Optics, No Date (Box 24, Folder 4)
  - Lunar Observations, No Date (Box 24, Folder 5)
  - Time in an Inhomogeneous Universe, No Date (Box 24, Folder 6)
  - Galaxy Formation, No Date (Box 24, Folder 7)
  - Cosmic Discovery, No Date (Box 24, Folder 8)
  - Understanding, 1991 (Box 24, Folder 9)
  - The Military and Astronomy, No Date (Box 24, Folder 10)
- VII. Photographs, Drawings, and Blueprints
  - Space rockets - figure drawings (Box 21, Folder 11-12)
  - Infrared Stellar Photometer Experiment photographs (Box 21, Folder 13)
  - Telescopic Rocket photographs (Box 21, Folder 14-18)
  - Telescopic Rocket work photographs (Box 21, Folder 19-20)
  - Telescopic Rocket Work negatives (Box 21, Folder 21)
  - Cornell Rocket program - drawings and diagrams (Box 21, Folder 22)
  - Cornell University Infrared Rocket Astronomy photographs (Box 21, Folder 23)
  - Fabry-Perot Interferometer photographs (Box 21, Folder 24)
  - Brochure: photographs re. Cornell research in Far Infrared Rocket Astronomy featuring a cryogenically cooled telescope (Box 21, Folder 25)
  - Oversized Materials
    - Housing Infrared Experiment NF 3.162 (Folder 1)
    - Drawings for Shuttle Sortie; Space Rocket figure drawings (Folder 2)
    - Liquid Cooled Rocket Borne Telescope blueprints (Folder 3)
    - Infrared Sensing Telescope Launching drawings (Folder 4)
- Publications
  - 1. Free Surface of Liquids as an Optical Element, M. J. Block and M. Harwit, J.O.S.A., 48, 480 (1958). (Box 21)
  - 2. Detection of Signals Far Below the Photon Noise Limit, M. Harwit, Proc. I.R.I.S. Washington Symposium, Feb. (1960). (Box 21)
  - 3. Measurement of Fluctuations from a Source in Thermal Equilibrium, M. Harwit, M.I.T. (RLE + NSL joint publications), TR 364 (1960). (Box 21, Folder 26)
  - 4. Noise Measurements and Photoconductor Characteristics, M. Harwit, J.O.S.A. Advertisement, 50, No. 6, vi (1960). (Box 21, Folder 27)
  - 5. Measurement of Thermal Fluctuations in Radiation, M. Harwit, Physical Rev., 120, 1551 (1960). (Box 21, Folder 27)
  - 6. Can Gravitational Forces Alone Account for Galaxy Formation in a steady State Universe, M. Harwit, MNRAS, 122, 47 (1961). (Box 21, Folder 27)
  - 7. Can Gravitational Forces Alone Account for Galaxy Formation in a Steady-State Universe II -- Bondi-Gold Universes, M. Harwit, MNRAS, 123, 257 (1961). (Box 21, Folder 27)
  - 8. On the Fate of Intergalactic Bridges, F. Hoyle, M. Harwit, PASP, Vol. 74, No. 202, June 1962. (Box 21)
  - 9. Plasma Dynamics in Comets I. - Plasma Instability, F. Hoyle and M. Harwit, Ap. J., 135, 867 (1962). (Box 21, Folder 27)
  - 10. Plasma Dynamics in Comets II. - Influence of Magnetic Fields, M. Harwit and F. Hoyle, Ap. J., 135, 875 (1962). (Box 21, Folder 27)
  - 11. Dust, Radiation Pressure and Star Formation, M. Harwit, Ap. J., 136, 832 (1962). (Box 21, Folder 27)
  - 12. Expected Near Infrared Radiation from Interstellar Molecular Hydrogen, R. H. Gould and M. Harwit, Ap. J., 137, 694 (1963). (Box 21, Folder 27)
  - 13. Infrared Appearance of Different Zodiacal Cloud Models, M. Harwit, Congr. + Coll. de l' Université de Liège, 26, 506 (1964). (Box 21, Folder 27)
  - 14. Origins of the Zodiacal Dust Cloud, M. Harwit, JGR, 68, 2171 (1963). (Box 21, Folder 27)
  - 15. Origins of the Zodiacal Dust Cloud II, M. Harwit, Ann. of NY Acad. of Sci., 119, 68-71 (1964). (Box 21, Folder 27)
  - 16. On the Transition Between Long and Short Period Comets, M. Harwit, CSUAC 18, Congr. + Coll. de l'Université de Liège, 37, 489 (1966). (Box 21, Folder 27)
  - 17. A Liquid Nitrogen Cooled Rocket Borne, Infrared Telescope, M. Harwit, D. P. McNutt, K. Shivanandan, and B. J. Zajac, CRSR 230, Appl. Opt., 5, 1732 (1966). (Box 21, Folder 27)
  - 18. Results of the First Infrared Astronomical Rocket Flight, M. Harwit, D. P. NcNutt, K. Shivanandan and B. J. Zajac, CRSR 229, Astronomical Journal, 71, 1026 (1966). (Box 21, Folder 28)
  - 19. Infrared Rocket Observations, M. Harwit, D. P. McNutt, K. Shivanandan and B. J. Zajac, in "Infrared Astronomy" ed. Brancazio and Cameron, Gordon and Breach, p. 91 (1968). (Box 21)
  - 20. On the Detection of Water on the Moon, M. Werner, T. Gold, M. Harwit, Planetary and Space Science, 15, 771 (1967). (Box 21)
  - 21. Infrared and Radio Appearance of Cocoon Stars, K. Davidson and M. Harwit, Ap. J., 148, 443 (1967). (Box 21)
  - 22. Origin and Evolution of the Family of Sun Grazing Comets, M. Harwit, CSUAC, 64, Cornell University (1967). (Box 21)
  - 23. The Cloud of Interplanetary Boulders, M. Harwit, in "The Zodiacal Light and the Interplanetary Medium." ed. J. L. Weinberg, NASA SP-150, p. 307 (1967). (Box 21, Folder 28)
  - 24. "Spontaneously" Split Comets, M. Harwit, Ap. J., 151, 789 (1968). (Box 21)
  - 25. Near Infrared Night Sky Background, M. Harwit, K. Fuhrmann and M. Werner, Transactions of the Royal Society A, 264, 273 (1969). (Box 21, Folder 28)
  - 26. Infrared Rocket Astronomy, M. Harwit in "Small Rocket Instrumentation Techniques," K. Maeda, ed., North Holland Publ. Co., Amsterdam, p. 155 (1969). (Box 21)
  - 27. Observational Evidence for the Existence of Dense Clouds of Interstellar Molecular Hydrogen, M. Werner, M. Harwit, Ap. J., 154, 881 (1968). (Box 21, Folder 28)
  - 28. Means of Measuring the Earth's Velocity through the 3Â° Radiation Field, J. J. Condon and M. Harwit, Phys. Rev. Let., 20, 1309 and 21, 58 (1968). (Box 21, Folder 29)
  - 29. A Wide-Spacing, Mechanical Collimator, J. F. McGrath and M. Harwit, Appl. Opt., 8, 837 (1969). (Box 21, Folder 29)
  - 30. Sequential Encoding with Multislit Spectrometers, J. A. Decker, Jr. and M. Harwit, Appl. Opt., 7, 2205 (1968). (Box 21, Folder 29)
  - 31. False Signal Rejection in Optical-Infrared Collision Warning Systems, J. A. Decker, Jr., M. G. Morris and M. Harwit, AIAA, Journal of Aircraft, 6, 169 (1969). (Box 21, Folder 29)
  - 32. Preliminary Observations of the Far Infrared Night Sky Background Radiation, K. Shivanandan, J. R. Houck and M. Harwit, Phys. Rev. Let., 21, 1460 (1968). (Box 21, Folder 29)
  - 33. Rocket Borne Liquid Helium Cooled Telescope, M. Harwit, J. R. Houck and K. Fuhrmann, Appl. Opt., 8, 473 (1969). (Box 21, Folder 29)
  - 34. Limb Darkening on the Earth's Night Side at Wavelengths of 1 to 3 Âµ and 3 - 7.5 Âµ, J. Pipher, M. Harwit, D. P. McNutt, P. D. Feldman and K. Shivanandan, J. Atm. Sci., 26, 617 (1969). (Box 21)
  - 35. Far-Infrared Observations of the Night Sky, J. R. Houck and M. Harwit, Science, 164, 1271 (1969). (Box 21, Folder 29)
  - 36. Far-Infrared Night Sky Emission Above 120 Kilometers, J. R. Houck and M. Harwit, Ap. J., 157, L45 (1969). (Box 21, Folder 29)
  - 37. Experimental Operation of a Hadamard Spectrometer, John A. Decker, Jr. and Martin Harwit, Appl. Opt., 8, 2252 (1969). (Box 21)
  - 38. Codes for Multiplex Spectrometry, Neil J. A. Sloane, Terrence Fine, Perry G. Phillips and Martin Harwit, Appl. Opt., 8, 2103 (1969). (Box 21, Folder 29)
  - 39. Rocket Observations of Far Infrared Radiation Which May Emanate from the Upper Atmosphere, J. R. Houck and M. Harwit, Proceedings of the 1969 COSPAR Conference, "Space Research X," North Holland, p. 532 (1970). (Box 21, Folder 29)
  - 40. Doubly Multiplexed Dispersive Spectrometers, M. Harwit, P. G. Phillips, T. Fine, N. J. A. Sloane, Appl. Opt., 9, 1149 (1970). (Box 21, Folder 30)
  - 41. Possibility of a Terrestrial Component in the Doppler Shifted Zodiacal Light, V. Vanýsek and M. Harwit, Nature, 225, 1231 (1970). (Box 21)
  - 42. Far-Infrared Observations of the Night Sky: Different Data, J. R. Houck and M. Harwit, Science, 167, 1277 (Box 21, Folder 30)
  - 43. Is Magnetic Alignment of Interstellar Dust Really Necessary M. Harwit, Nature, 226, 61 (1970). (Box 21, Folder 30)
  - 44. Alignment of Interstellar Grains by Starlight, M. Harwit, Bull. of the Astro. Inst. of Czechoslovakia, 21, 204 (1970). (Box 21, Folder 30)
  - 45. Infrared Astronomical Background Radiation, M. Harwit, Rev. d. Nuovo Cimento, 2, 253 (1970). (Box 21, Folder 30)
  - 46. Observational Upper Limits to the Electromagnetic Energy Radiated by Normal Galaxies, M. Harwit, J. R. Houck and R. Wagoner, Nature, 228, 451 (1970). (Box 21, Folder 30)
  - 47. Possible Method for Determining the Planck Constant of Cosmic photons, M. Harwit, Nature, 228, 845 (1970). (Box 21, Folder 30)
  - 48. Vzdálená infra?ervená emise no?ní oblohy, M. Harwit, ?í?e Hv?zd, 51, 121 (1970). (Box 21)
  - 49. Nedávné výzkumy o pulsarech, M. Harwit, C;s. D;asopis pro fyziku, A20, 326 (1970). (Box 21)
  - 50. Alignment of Dust Particles in Comet Tails, M. Harwit and V. Vanýsek, Bull. of the Astro. Inst. of Czechoslovakia, 22, 18 (1971). (Box 21, Folder 31)
  - 51. A Possible Observational Test to Determine Variations of Planck's Constant on a Cosmic Scale, M. Harwit, Bull. of the Astro. Inst. of Czechoslovakia, 22, 22 (1971). (Box 21, Folder 31)
  - 52. Rocket-Infrared Observations of the Interplanetary Medium, Baruch T. Soifer, J. R. Houck and Martin Harwit, Ap. J. Lett., 168, L 73 (1971). (Box 21, Folder 31)
  - 53. Spectrometric Imager, Martin Harwit, Appl. Opt., 10, 1415 (1971). (Box 21, Folder 31)
  - 54. Rocket-Infrared Four-Color Photometry of the Galaxy's Central Regions, J. R. Houck, B. T. Soifer, Judith L. Pipher and Martin Harwit, Ap. J. Lett., 169, L31 (1971). (Box 21, Folder 31)
  - 55. A search for Near-Infrared Emission of Interstellar Molecular Hydrogen, T. R. Gull and M. O. Harwit, Ap. J., 168, 15 (1971). (Box 21, Folder 31)
  - 56. Submillimetre Observations of the Night Sky Emission Above 120 Kilometres, Judith L. Pipher, J. R. Houck, Barrie W. Jones and Martin Harwit, Nature, 231, 375 (1971). (Box 21, Folder 31)
  - 57. U. S. Patent #3,572,928, John Decker, Jr. and Martin O. Harwit, Patented March 30, 1971, "Aircraft Proximity Warning System." (Box 21, Folder 31)
  - 58. Book Reviews, Icarus, 14, 179 (1971). Atlas of Cometary Forms, Structures Near the Nucleus. Jürgen Rahe, Bertram Donn and Karl Wurm, NASA SP-198 (1969). Isophotometric Atlas of Comets, Part I., W. Hogner and N. Richter, Johann Ambrosius Barth, Leipzig (1969). (Box 21, Folder 31)
  - 59. A New Multiplexing Spectrometer with Large Throughput, Perry G. Phillips, Martin Harwit and Neil J. A. Sloane, Aspen International Conference on Fourier Spectroscopy (1970). G. Vanasse, A. T. Stair, D. J. Baker, editors, U. S. Air Force (1971), AFCRL-71-0019 (Box 21)
  - 60. U. S. Patent #3,578,980, John Decker, Jr. and Martin O. Harwit, patented May 18, 1971, "Spectral Analysis Using Masks Having Different Combinations of Transmitting and Non-Transmitting Portions." (Box 21)
  - 61. Doubly Multiplexing Dispersive Spectrometer, Perry G. Phillips and Martin Harwit, Appl. Opt., 10, 2780 (1971). (Box 21, Folder 31)
  - 62. U. S. Patent #3,625,612, John A. Decker, Jr., Martin O. Harwit and D. S. Sarcia, Patented December 7, 1971, "Optical Derotator Employing Mirror Pairs to View a Rotating Body." (Box 21)
  - 63. Why Many Infrared Astronomical Sources Emit at 100 Âµm, Martin Harwit, B. T. Soifer, J. R. Houck and Judith Pipher, Nature, Physical Science, 236, 103 (1972). (Box 21, Folder 31)
  - 64. Operation of a LHe Rocket-Borne Infrared Telescope, Martin Harwit, Published in the Proceedings of Cryogenic Workshop, NASA George C. Marshall Space Flight Center, March 29-30 (1972). (Box 21)